Want to learn Japanese anywhere,
anytime? Get the Innovative Language 101
app for
free. Hi everyone, welcome to Basic
Japanese Writing, the fastest, easiest,
and most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet. You've learned all the 46
hiragana characters from the previous
lessons. Now it's time to move on to
katakana. In this lesson you learn about
katakana, how it is different from
hiragana and the five katakana
vows. Katakana is the exact equivalent
of hiragana when it comes to
pronunciation. The main difference is
how the characters look and when they
are used. Katakana characters tend to
look more angular. There is also almost
nothing in common with how katakana
characters look compared to their
hiragana counterparts except for a few
characters. So why is it that we need to
learn two basic writing systems when
they both sound exactly the same? The
main use of katakana is to differentiate
and spell out foreign words using the
Japanese syllary. This makes it easier
for Japanese people to know how they are
approximately pronounced. Most country
names, foreign names, and all learn
words from the modern era are written in
katakana. Katakana is also used to write
down onomatotopia sounds like how you
would see sound effects written in
Japanese
manga. It is also used to write some
technical or scientific words. Finally,
katakana is also used for emphasis just
like how English uses
italics. Okay, it's time to learn your
first katakana. Are you ready? Here we
go. This is the katakana character.
A to remember this character, try
comparing it with an axe. Do you see it?
Next up is the katakana character.
E. Think of this character as an easel
on its
side. The third one is the
katakana.
Uh katakana actually looks like an
angular version of the
hilagana.
Here's a special use of the daken unique
to katakana. It is added to the
character U to signify the letter V.
However, there is no V sound in
Japanese. So, most people would
pronounce this as a V
sound. This is the katakana character.
E. Try imagining this character as
elevator
doors. Now our final character for this
lesson
O to remember O try to think of it as an
opera
singer. Unlike hiragana where long vowel
sounds are indicated using another vowel
character, katakana writing makes use of
the novashi. So instead of writing a
with two a characters, we would write it
like
this. Literally novasho means stretching
ver. So when you see it, just remember
that you have to stretch the vowel of
the character that comes before
it. In order to accommodate more sounds
available from foreign words, katakana
uses the small versions of the v
characters to make diagraphs outside of
those used in Japanese. For example,
since Japanese doesn't have a character
for a wi or v sound, the katakana paired
with a small e or is used to denote
those
sounds.
We because they are diagraphs though
they would still be pronounced for the
same duration as all the other
syllables. Here are the diagraphs you
can form using the katakana vows alone.
Yeah,
we
V
B. Since most Japanese people can't
distinguish between the V and B sounds,
these last four diagramraphs tend to
also be spelled using the B characters
B, B, B, and B.
I'll be teaching you more katakana
diagramraphs when we encounter the
character that the small vowels could be
paired up
with. Let's see all the characters
again. A
e
v o. Here are the new diagramraphs as
well. Yeah,
we
w
b v
Now, let's review what you've learned.
I'll show you a character or a word and
give you time to say them.
Ready?
Oh. So, even though we move to katakana,
don't forget your hiragana
characters. It's like an easel on its
side.
Remember the
cow
we Japanese people would say when we
realized something like ah I forgot my
wallet.
Ooh. Oh, on the other hand is what we
say when we are amazed.
Great job. Remember, even if foreign
words are adopted by Japanese, this
doesn't mean they are pronounced the
same way as the original word, you still
need to pronounce them using the
Japanese syllary in order for Japanese
people to understand you.
Okay, let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've
learned. In this lesson, you've learned
the five katakana vowels, A, E, U, E,
and O. You also learned that the
character U can be modified by a duct to
represent the B sound. And finally, some
new diagramraphs. Yeah,
we
w
B. You've now mastered 51 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone. Welcome to
basic Japanese writing. The fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
[Music]
alphabet. You've learned these five
katakana characters from the previous
lesson.
In this lesson, you'll learn five new
characters. Remember the duck? Then
we'll see it again in this
lesson. The first katakana character for
this lesson
is
K. Katakana. Actually looks like a more
angular version of hira without this
stroke. Just like in the K column of
hiragana, the K column of katakana can
also be changed by the daken or tenten
mark. We put it in the upper right
corner. So now it will be pronounced G C
G C K C K C K C K C K C K C K C K C K C
K
G. Okay, next up is the katakana
character
Ki
Ki also looks like its hiraagana
counterpart but without this part at the
bottom. Just like the katakana, we could
also put a den on it. K with a den is
pronounced as g k g
G. The third one is the
katakana
C. If hiragana is a cuckoo's beak, then
try remembering katakana as the cuckoo's
tail. Let's add a duck to c as well.
It's now pronounced as G C G C
G. This is a katakana character.
K. Try looking at it from this angle and
you'll see a letter
K. Just like the first three characters,
K can be modified by a duct. K with a
duct ten is pronounced as G K G K
G. And our final character for this
lesson is the
katakana
co. Imagine this character as a road
with two
corners. Now, do you remember what court
sounds like with a duck? It will be go
co go co go. Let's see all the
characters again. C G K G C G K K K K K
K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K G G G G G
G G G G G G G G G G G G G G G co
go. Now let's review what you've
learned. I show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready? What? Which one is the katakana
k? It's this one. Just find a sideways
K. It has a duct ten so
it's remember it's a diagramraph so
don't say that e
sound as in mount
huji echo this means eco-friendly it's a
popular katakana word right
now gia it means gear
Here. Co. Caka means
caka. Cake. This is cake.
Yum. This is the sound crows
make. This means cool or sexy.
Goo. This is anomato pier for the sound
of snoring or stomach
grumbling. Okay. As you can guess, it
means
okay. Great job. Have you forgotten some
hiragana characters? Many katakana
characters look very similar to their
hiragana counterparts. So it will
actually take you less effort to
remember if you've mastered all the
hiragana already. So keep on reviewing
the hiragana characters even if we are
doing the katakana characters already.
Okay, let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned. In this
lesson, you learned C and G, K and G, C
and G, K and G, and C and go.
You've now mastered 56 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone. Welcome to
basic Japanese writing. The fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 10
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learn five
new katakana characters.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
sa. This one looks like a
saddle and might get you confused. So to
differentiate the two, just look at
where the second and third strokes end.
The ones for s end at the center and the
ones for s end at the sides. All of the
characters in this column can also be
altered by a duct ten. Do you remember
what sa with the duct ten sounds like?
It's z sa z sa
z. Okay, next up is the kakana
character.
She try to think of she as a sinking
ship. Let's add a duct tan to she.
Remember, it's not supposed to sound
like Z. She with a duct tan is
pronounced as
G. She g she g. She is the only Japanese
character that produces the sh sound and
the only original Japanese syllable
sounds available are sha she sh and sh.
The diagraph sh is then created by
adding a small katakana e to sh. This
enables Japanese people to say words
like chef and share. Also, since she
with a duct ten is the only sound in
Japanese to produce a J sound, the same
is done to J, creating the J
diagramraph. This allows Japanese people
to say words like jelly or
widget. The third one is the katakana
s. Think of this one as a person skiing.
Let's add a duct t to s as well. It now
becomes
s. This is the katakana character.
Se katakana is also another character
that looks like an angular version of
its hiragana counterpart. It's also just
missing this part on the top
right. Let's modify set with a den. It
is now pronounced as z se
z. And our final character for this
lesson is the katakana.
So,
so to remember so just imagine it as a
soft served ice cream
cone. Now can you go and say what so
sounds like with the duct? It will
be so z so z. Let's see all the
characters again.
Z,
she
s J so Z and a new diagramraphs sh and
J. Now let's review what you've learned.
I'll show you a character or a word and
give you time to say them. Ready?
S. It's G. Which one is the
katakana? It's this
one. Oh, remember the opera
singer?
Oh, this refers to the gas in the gas
lines and not gasoline or the gas state
of
matter. This means
Asia
ski means skiing. Don't confuse it with
meaning to
like
ski. This means
co source. It means source or sometimes
source. Kasakasa. This is the Japanese
for wrestling. It also means
dry. Whiskey. This means whiskey. Japan
has a few well-known brands of
whiskey. This means to share. You can
actually find it in the Japanese
Facebook
sites. Great job. Did you know when you
ask for ice in the store, you wouldn't
actually get ice, but ice cream instead?
Japanese people tend to contract popular
long words. So, it's best to research
first before turning English words into
katakana words directly. Okay, let's
wrap up this lesson by recapping what
you've learned. In this lesson, you
learned Sa and Z, she and J, S and Z, S
and Z, so and Z, and the diagramraphs SH
and
J. You've now mastered 61 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone, welcome to
basic Japanese writing. The fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 15
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learned the
five katakana characters under the T
column.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
t. Think of it as a person holding a
tablet. Just like their hiragana
counterparts, all of the katakana in
this column can be altered by a duct as
well. Ta with a den is d
t. Okay. Next up is the
katakana
chi
chi. Try to imagine katakana chi as a
chicken. Now let's add a duct tan to ch.
Remember it's not pronounced D. Actually
chi with a duct is pronounced as G chi G
J G J G J G J G J G J G J G J G J G J G
ch G G just like its hiragana
counterpart G is very rarely used. Just
like she is the only sh sound in
Japanese, chi is the only one with a ch
sound in Japanese.
The only syllables that were originally
available are
cha ch and ch. So making the chat
diagramraph allows Japanese people to
say long words like chair or
actually. The third katakana for this
lesson is
t. T looks like a tuna fish's head.
Does Kataku remind you of Kataki? They
look very similar, don't they? Here's a
great way to figure out which one is
which. Just remember the strokes of
their hiragana counterpart. Hiragana
starts from the top and curves up at the
end. The two short lines of kataki
aligns with this part and both
characters ends by going
up on the other hand starts from the
left and curves down at the end. The two
short lines of kataku align with this
part and both characters ends by going
down instead. Okay, let's add a den to t
as well. It's pronounced as t. Listen
carefully.
Tai is also available for katakana as
well. It serves the same function of
lengthening the consonant after it when
found at the end of the word. The tu
acts like a glutter stop for words
spelled using
katakana. Next is the katakana character
T. Katakana looks like a telephone pole
bent at an
angle. Let's modify T with a duct ten.
It is now pronounced
as T T.
Since chi has the ch sound, the t column
doesn't have a native t syllable sound.
So for long words that have this sound,
the t diagramraph is
created. And since chi with a den is
pronounced g, a long word with the d
syllable on the other hand can be
written using the d
diagramraph. Our final character for
this lesson is the katakana to
to looks like a side view of a to
temple. What does to sound like with a
duct ten? To with a duct ten is
pronounced do. Remember to do to to do.
Just as there is no native T syllable in
Japanese, there isn't a native T
syllable as well. In order to say fallen
names or long words with a T syllable,
the T diagramraph is used. By adding a
duct tenant to the two diagramraph,
spell out words with the D syllable.
Let's see all the characters again.
T do and the new diagramraphs
ch to and
d. Now let's review what you've learned.
I'll show you a character or a word and
give you time to say them.
Ready
T
do
me. Which one is a
katakana? It's this one. Remember the
stroke of their hiragana counterparts
and you'll easily distinguish between
these
two
tai means
Thailand. It's
cheeseto this means a romantic
date is
Germany switch it means
switch this means soccer or football
goal
pool. Refers to outdoor
activities. This is what we call roller
coasters. Great job. Confused about how
to properly spell long words in
katakana? Searching in an online
dictionary is the best way to go. More
and more and foreign words are being
incorporated into Japanese and many even
have more than one accepted spelling.
Okay, let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned. In this
lesson, you learned T and D, she and J,
T, D, and T, T
and the
diagramraphs, T, D, T, and
D. You've now mastered 66 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone. Welcome to
Basic Japanese Writing, the fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 20
katakana characters in the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learned the
five katakana characters of the N
column.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
na
na. Think of na as a curved
knife. Okay, next up is the
katakana. Remember the hiragana.
Just remove this part and make the line
straight and you get the
katakana. The third one is the
katakana. Try to think of it as a
news. This is the katakana
character.
N. Think of N as a nest in a
tree. And our final character for this
lesson is the katakana.
No.
No. It's easy to remember this one. It's
a no sign just like its hiragana
counterpart but without the circle.
Let's see all the characters
again.
N. Now, let's review what you've
learned. I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready? No.
me.
She s try not to confuse it
with po.
It's a tuna
fish. This is the material or punch line
of a
joke. This actually means
notebook. This refers to elderly
people. Canoe. It means canoe.
This means the
internet. This means smiling from ear to
ear. Designer. It means
designer. Great job. As you can see, so
many falling words end up being
translated using the katakana sy. and
you'll be tempted to just translate
English words directly all the time.
However, not all words catch on in
Japanese. Make sure to learn more
Japanese words first. Okay, let's wrap
up this lesson by recapping what you've
learned. In this lesson, you learned the
katakana
characters and
no, you've now mastered 71 Japanese
characters.
Hi everyone, welcome to basic Japanese
writing, the fastest, easiest, and most
fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 25
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learned the
five katakana characters in the H
column. We'll be using the daken and
haken as well.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
ha. To remember ha, imagine it as a roof
of a
house. Do you remember how to pronounce
ha with a den? It will be B h B h B. And
what will be its sound if we put a haken
on it
instead? Do you remember H with a haken
is pronounced P H P P P P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P P P P H H H H H H H H H H H
H H H H H H H H H H P P P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P P P P
P. Okay, next up is the katakana
character.
He can you see it as a side of
heel? Now let's add a duct ten to
he with a duct ten is pronounced as b he
he b he he he b. And how will it sound
with a haken? It's going to be P he he p
he he he
P. The third katakana for this lesson is
H. Remember it's not who or who but
somewhat in between. H
who to remember the katakana h try to
think of it as the tip of a foot.
Let's try adding a duct t to h as well.
What do you think it will sound like?
It's pronounced as b. Listen carefully.
H b h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h
h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h
h h b
b. Now let's try it with haken. It
becomes P H P P P P P P P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P H H H H H H H H H H H H H H
H H H H H H H P P P P P P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P P P P H H H H H H H H H H H
H H H H H H H H H is special as it's the
only syllable in Japanese to have a
sound very close to an F sound. You
combine h with smaller versions of the
katakana vowels to make a whole f column
f
and take note that you don't combine a
small u to h since it already ends in an
sound.
Next is the katakana character
he looks exactly like it hilagana
counterpart with no
exceptions. Let's modify he with a den.
It is now pronounced as B he he b he B.
And when he is modified with a handm it
will be pronounced as P he p he he
p. Our final character for this lesson
is the katakana
h. You can think of H as a shining holy
cross. What does H sound like with a
duct? H with a duct is pronounced po h
po h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h
h po. And with a hand, it will be po h
h po p po. Let's see all the characters
again. H B P He B P H B P P P P P P P P
P P P P P P P P P P P P He B P H B P and
the new diagramraphs
F P and
P. Now, let's review what you've
learned. I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready
P.
He what? Remember the white
swan?
B
C N. It looks like a knife.
Remember, this could mean bass, the
musical instrument or the vases in
baseball.
It means to slack
off. This means
coffee. This refers to department
store. Business. Business means
business. Party. This means party. Yeah.
Pika pika. This means shiny or
sparkling. Go. This is anomato for
rushing
water. Great job. Did you know that many
long words have become so popular that
they even become verbs or adjectives?
Some examples
are meaning to
share meaning smart looking and meaning
to slack off. This last one comes from
an abbreviation of
sabotage. Okay, let's wrap up this
lesson by recapping what you've learned.
In this lesson, you learned ha ba and p
he b and p h b and p he b and p h h h h
h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h po and
po and the diagramraphs
f
and you've Now master 76 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone, welcome to
basic Japanese writing. The fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these sachi
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learn five
new katakana characters.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
ma
ma. Think of ma as a manta
ray. Okay, next up is the katakana
character
me. To remember me, look for the line in
the middle.
The third one is the
katakana
m looks like a moose's
antlers. Could you tell m from m? Here's
an easy way to do it. Just look for the
horizontal line. If it's above, then
it's a m. And if it's under, then it's a
m.
This is the katakana character.
Me. Just draw a rectangle around it and
you got
male. And our final character for this
lesson is the katakana
mo. Mo looks very similar to its
hiragana counterpart. The only
difference is that the third stroke
doesn't intersect the first
one. Let's see all the characters again.
M
m. Now, let's review what you've
learned. I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready?
Which one is the
katakamu? It's this
one. It's the first character I taught
you. A
This means games including iPad and
video
games. Is the abbreviation and the more
common term to refer to a smartphone in
Japan.
Memor this means to take a memo or to
take
note. This actually refers to an
illustration as opposed to an actual
picture. It means digital camera.
Here's another abbreviation that means
mass communication or
media is an eraser. It literally means
erasing
rubber. This means
Mexico. Great job. As I've said before,
katakana is used to write phony words
and names. So, why don't you try and
write your name in the comments using
katakana? We can also help you with the
spelling since it can be tricky
sometimes. Okay, let's wrap up this
lesson by recapping what you've learned.
In this lesson, you learned the katakana
characters. Ma,
m,
and you've now mastered 81 Japanese
characters. Hi everyone, welcome to
Basic Japanese Writing, the fastest,
easiest, and most fun way to master the
Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 35
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, we are skipping
ahead to the R column where you'll learn
five new katakana
characters. The first katakana character
for this lesson is
Try to think of la as a ling
chair. Next up is the
katakana.
Li le looks exactly like its hiragana
counterpart but without the honey part.
The third one is the
katakana. To remember this character,
think of it as the roots of a
tree. This is the katakana character
le. Think of le as a razor blade.
And now our final character for this
lesson is the
katakana.
Lo looks like a robot's
mouth. Let's see all the characters
again.
L. Now let's review what you've learned.
I show you a character or a word and
give you time to say them. Ready?
L
go
m this means
hotel. Toilet. This means the toilet.
It's best to remember this one if you
are going to
Japan. TV. It means TV. As you can see,
it's short for
television. It's the popular Japanese
pastime.
is the United
Kingdom. It means part-time
work. This means to propose
marriage. This means credit card.
Japanese people wouldn't understand if
you just say card. So, make sure to say
the whole
thing. Great job. Do you know what the
ultimate flash card game for reading
hiragana and katakana is? Try doing
Japanese kok. You'll need to read the
characters first in order to sing
properly. I suggest starting with some
slow songs first. Okay, let's wrap up
this lesson by recapping what you've
learned. In this lesson, you learned
la
and just like in the hiragana lesson,
please take note that we skipped the y
column this time so that we could
discuss all the Japanese diagramraphs in
the next
lesson. You've now mastered 86 Japanese
characters.
Hi everyone, welcome to basic Japanese
writing. The fastest, easiest, and most
fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet. You've learned these 40
katakana characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learned
three katakana characters in the Y
column and the rest of the diagramraphs
in katakana.
The first katakana character for this
lesson is
Ya.
Ya. Ya. Actually looks like its hilagana
counterpart, but a bit more angular and
without this
stroke. This is the katakana character.
You.
You. Imagine you as a periscope of a U
boat
underwater. Our final character for this
lesson is the katakana
y. It's like a yolk pulled by two oxen.
Just like in hiragana, diagraphs in
katakana are also formed by adding a
small ya yu or y to a consonant plus e
syllable. Remember, they are set for the
same duration as all the previous
syllables that you've learned. Pronounce
them by gliding to the y sound and do
not pronounce the e sound.
C
Q
Y
sh
P me m me m me m me m me m me m me m me
m me m me m me m
Let's see all the characters again.
Yo, and the diagramraphs in
katakana. Now, let's review what you've
learned. I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready?
Do he remember the smiling mouth going?
Da. This is the time table for buses and
trains. Menu. This means
menu. Ju. It's
juice. T-shirt. It means t-shirt.
Barbecue. This means
barbecue. Chocolate. This is
chocolate. This is a cat's meow in
Japanese. This refers to a bank
card. Great job. As I've said before,
Japanese uses three scripts, hiragana,
katakana, and kanji. However, recently
Japanese also started to make use of
Roman letters just like
in we even have the expression energy,
which is an abbreviation of no
good. Okay, let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned. In this
lesson, you learned the katakana
characters ya y and y and all the
Japanese
diagramraphs. You've now mastered 89
Japanese characters. Only three left to
go. Hi everyone. Welcome to basic
Japanese writing. The fastest, easiest,
and most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet.
[Music]
You've learned these 43 katakana
characters from the previous
lessons. In this lesson, you learned the
last three characters in basic Japanese
writing. The first katakana character
for this lesson is
W. This character looks like a wine
glass.
Katakana and W looks similar, doesn't
it? Well, just remember that W is wider
and C has more curved
lines. Okay, next up is the katakana
character
W. It is also commonly said as
O. To remember katakana, try to think of
it as part of the world Olympic torch.
Our final collector for this lesson is
the
katakana. It looks like a spacecraft
entering the Earth's
atmosphere. Many people confuse so and
because they look very similar. One
thing that could help distinguish the
two is that so is slimmer.
Just like the hiragana, you can never
start a word with a katakana. It can
only be found in the middle or at the
end of
words. Again, just like in hiragana, the
pronunciation of n varies a bit
depending on the syllable that comes
after it. It sounds like an M sound when
it comes before a b or p sound. For
example, haga and camp. It can also
sound like an N sound when it comes
before a G sound like
in. Let's say all the characters again.
W or O. And
finally, now let's review what you've
learned. I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them.
Ready?
Which one is the
katak? It's this
one. Just like a tsunami. Which one is
the
katakana? It's this one. The wider one.
This means convenience store. You'll
find a lot of them in
Japan. Why? This is an onomato pier for
a noisy
crowd. Air. This means AC or air
conditioning. It's lame. It's a famous
noodles and soup dish in
Japan. One, this is a dog's bark in
Japanese. This means a gift.
This actually refers to contact
lenses. This is a general term for men
working for a company. They are mostly
distinguished by their shirt and nexai
attire. Great job. There's actually a
very fun word game in Japanese
called. Basically, one person says a
word and the next person says another
word which starts with the last syllable
of the word said by the previous person.
But remember, no Japanese word starts
with N. So, anyone who gives a word
ending with it
loses. Okay, let's wrap up this lesson
by recapping what you've learned. In
this lesson, you learned the katakana
characters
and you've now mastered all 92 hiragana
and katakana
characters. Here are the 46 katakana
characters. They are the exact
equivalent of the 46 hiragana
characters. But I used to write most
country names, foreign names, long
words, sounds and technical or
scientific words. They are also used to
indicate emphasis. These are the five
vowel sounds and the rest are
combination of a consonant and a vowel
sound except for n. A long vowel sound
in katakana is signified by a noash
instead of another vowel calixa. On the
other hand, the den or tenten mark is
used the same way in katakana to signify
that the consonant of the syllable is
voiced. It can modify the characters
under the k, s, t, and h columns. Unique
to katakana, the daken is also used with
the character u in order to signify the
letter v. The haken or maru mark which
makes the consonant sound plusive is
also used and it's unique to the h
column as well. There are more unique
diagramraphs in katakana to accommodate
the sounds from foreign words. This
include
y we
v j ch t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t
t t t d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d
d d d t d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d
d d d d
f and f. The rest are formed by adding a
small ya yu or y to a consonant plus e
syllable just like in hilagana.
Pronunciation of katakana characters
doesn't change except for the following
with alternate
pronunciations. W is actually more
commonly pronounced as o and n can
sometimes be pronounced n
or depending on the syllable that comes
after it.
Congratulations, you now know all of the
characters making up the Japanese basic
alphabet. The next step now is to start
learning Kanji to be able to unlock more
Japanese. Try watching our Kani series
here at
Japaneseport101.com and you'll pick up
on how to use kanji in no time. Before
you go, practice writing the following
words on your own. And to learn more
Japanese, go to
japesport101.com. Do you know the top 10
conversational phrases in Japanese?
Here's a hint. Kawaii is not one of
them. Find out the most important words
you need in order to have fun, fluent
conversations with native Japanese
speakers. Click the link to get the top
10 conversational phrases in Japanese
for
free. See you in another lesson.
[Music]
M. What's it