want to speak real Japanese from your
first lesson sign up for your free
lifetime account at
japanesepod101.com
hi everyone I'm Raisa welcome to basic
Japanese
writing in this series I'm going to
teach you how to master the Japanese
alphabet in the fastest easiest and most
fun way did you know written Japanese
actually uses three different Scripts
hiana kak
and Ki hiragana is the basic Japanese
alphabet contrary to the English
alphabet however each character
represents one Sy sound so every time
you see one specific character you know
that it will always sound the same way
the second script used in Japanese is
Katakana each Katakana character
represents the same syllable as it
hilana
counterpart however it is written a bit
differently and is used mostly for
foreign words these two make up the
Japanese alphabet and they will be the
focus of this series on the other hand
Kani characters represent a word or a
concept and unlike kagana and Katakana
there are thousands of them plus there
are also different leadings for each of
them this makes Kani characters harder
to master however it's important to
learn them as well because they are
essential in understanding Japanese
to learn more about kanji check out our
kanji series at Japanese Port 101.com
which I also host with
Alicia in this first lesson we will be
diving into hilana and you'll be
learning your first five
characters hiragana characters are the
most common of the three scripts because
it's used to write functional words like
grammatical particles and are also
commonly found at the end of adjectives
and and verbs there are also a lots of
vers that are more commonly written in
hiragana rather than kanji technically
hiragana characters could also be used
to substitute Kani characters that you
don't know how to write but don't use
this as an excuse not to learn Kani
there are 46 sagana characters and they
are commonly arranged in this
order take note that when Japanese is
written vertically you read it from
right to left
so we'll be starting with this column
these five characters are the five vowel
sounds in Japanese the rest of the
characters are made up of a consonant
sound and one of these vow sounds except
for the N character okay are you ready
to learn your first hilana here we go
this is the hilana
character to remember this Cala try
comparing it it with an
apple do you see
it next up is the hiragana
character think of this character as two
eyes side by side
e you can actually see E A Lot in
writing as it acts like a suffix to most
adjectives in Japanese
the third one is the
hiana to remember this character imagine
a boxer getting punched in the stomach
saying this is the H
character it looks like an energetic
ninja
whoosh
now our final character for this lesson
theana to remember o try to think of it
as a
UFO take a look at these two characters
do you remember this character on the
left that's right it's the hiragana H in
order to differentiate hiragana or o
from a just remember that o has a
floating stroke on the
side o is also often used in writing but
unlike it or is commonly found at the
beginning of words it is used to imply
politeness let's see all the characters
again a e u e
o now let's riew what you've learned
I'll show you a character or word and
give your time to say them
ready remember the energetic
ninja believe it or not it's actually a
word e means
stomach which one is
the it's the one that looks like an
and doesn't have a flirting stroke this
one I it means
love this one means up or
above means
no a this means blue
great job do you remember when I said
hiragana characters I used to spell out
the pronunciation of a Kani they are
placed above or beside Ai and written
smaller this use of hilana is called
fana okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've
learned in this lesson you've learned
the five hilag virus a e u e n o
you've now mastered your first five
Cals hi everyone welcome to basic
Japanese writing the fastest easiest and
most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned these five
hilana characters from the previous
lesson in this lesson you learn five new
characters and 10 new sounds how is that
possible stay tuned to find
out the first hilana character for this
lesson is C
cup need help remembering this one just
imagine it as a blade cutting a
stick cut is actually
aana that is used a lot since it is the
question marking particle in Japanese so
if you see a sentence ending in c it is
most probably a
question the hiragana also has another
reading once we add this Mark this Mark
is called D or
t it is made up of two lines that look
like a quotation mark symbol and it's
put on the upper right corner of the
character the D makes the consonant of
the syllable of voice so C with a D will
be pronounced as G voicing a consonant
simply means that you create a vibration
in your vocal cord when you say it g g
notice the
difference
G okay next up is
theana key looks like a key
just like the hilana all of the
characters in this column can be aled by
a d k with a d is pronounced as g k g
k the third one is the
hilana to remember this calor think of
it as a cuckoo speak cucko
let's add a d to C as well how do you
think it will sound like it's pronounced
as this is the hiragana
character K looks like a cake doesn't
it just just like the first three
characters K can be modified by a DCT K
with a DCT is pronounced as
K and our final character for this
lesson is
theana imagine this character as two koi
fish swimming around each
other
now can you go and say what Co sounds
like with a
duct it will be
go
go go let's see all the characters
again k
g k g co
go now let's give you what you've
learned I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them
ready K just like a key
remember c c actually means a
mosquito do you remember this
one it's
it
I
co this means to
write k k means
Shadow K this means to listen try not to
mix this up with
Kaku is
voice k k means key don't forget
it this means memory make sure not to
forget this one as
well aa aa is movie
this means
big great job I am wondering how do I
identify between a duct Mark and a
quotation mark don't worry in Japanese
we use corner brackets to signify quotes
and titles instead of quotation
marks okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've
learned in this lesson you learned C and
g k and G C and G K and G and Co and
go you've now mastered 10 characters and
15 Japanese syllable
sounds hi everyone welcome to basic
Japanese writing the fastest easiest and
most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned this tagana
characters from the previous lessons
in this lesson you learn five new
characters and again 10 new
sounds the first hiragana character for
this lesson is
s
sa this one looks like a s sign
face do you notice that sa and K look
similar a good tip to remember the
difference is that s is so sad that it
gets one less line all of the characters
in this column can also be altered by a
zaken can you try and guess what the new
sound will be it will be Z do you notice
the
difference
z
z okay next up is the hiragana Cal
sh sh
it looks like a fishing
hook let's add a DCT to sh how do you
think it will sound like now did you
think it was Z actually she with a DCT
is pronounced as G sh
G the third one is theana s
s s looks like a s p Stoll in a
glass let's add a du then to sue as well
what do you think it will sound like
it's pronounced
as this is the hiana character
set
set imagine set as a m facing sideways
it's about to say
something let's modify set with a
dent it is now pronounced as
z
z and our final character for this
lesson is the
so
so to remember so just imagine a zigzag
sewing
Stitch now can you go and say what so
sounds like with a duct it will be zo
so
so let's see all the characters again sa
Z she
now let's review what you've learned
I'll show you a character or group of
characters and give you time to say them
ready set which one is
theana it's this this one with one less
horizontal
line Z the word Z actually means
diagram did you remember this
one it's
O this one is
K Sushi is the famous Japanese
dish
J this means
accident SK ski means
like Sak this means to
bloom Z zo is
elephant okashi this means
sweets
means
alcohol Sao it means
last soo soo means
imagination try saying this long
one is a high school
student great job do you want to get
better at pronunciation try listening to
Japanese blogs and podcasts if you don't
know where to look we have a huge liely
at Japanese Port 101.com
remember nemonic help you associate
English words with the characters so
they do not necessarily teach you the
right
pronunciation okay let's wrap up this
lesson by recapping what you've
learned in this lesson you learned s and
Z she and Su
and and z and so and
so you've now mastered 15 characters and
25 Japanese syllable
sounds did you know that Japanese has a
word for the day after tomorrow you'll
get to know it in the next lesson when
we tackle the T
column before you go practice writing
the following words on your
own and to learn more Japanese go to
Japanese Port 101.com
hey guys what's your number one reason
for learning a language we asked our
other listeners this question and
compiled a list from their answers you
might be surprised to hear what a few of
them said check out the list in the link
below you'll even learn a little
Japanese while you're at
it see see you in the next lesson
mat hi everyone welcome to basic
Japanese writing the fastest easiest and
most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned these 15 hilana
characters from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn five
new characters 10 new syllable sounds
and an extra character function curious
stay tuned to learn all about
them the first hilana character for this
lesson is
t
t t actually looks like a t like a small
letter T N
A all of the hiragana in this column can
be aled by DCT as well can you guess
what the new sound will be after adding
a DCT to TP
it will be da T
da
da okay next up is the hiragana
character
ch
ch does a chi remind you of another
character it looks like the mirror image
of sa doesn't it just think of chi as a
cheer reader angry at s for copying
her
now let's add a duct to CH how do you
think it will sound like now is it D
actually CH with a is pronounced as G
it's just like a sh with a
G the third hiana for this lesson
is
this hiragana is very easy to remember s
looks like a tsunami
wave let's add the duct to two as well
how do you think it will sound like it's
actually pronounced as it's similar to S
with a
d listen
carefully actually T has a special
version that look looks like this and
it's called
CH literally
small it's actually just the smaller
size to so what do we use it
for the CH side is used to prolong the
consonant after it take a look at the
following examples and listen to how I
say
them to compare here are some words
without
it now listen as I say them side by
side when found at the end of the word
that CH acts like a Gro stop for example
ah next is aana character
looks like a dog
ta let's modify t with a d it is now
pronounced
as our final character for this lesson
is theana
to
to looks like a
tornado what does to sound like with the
DCT to with a DCT is pronounced do to do
to do let's see all the characters again
T
da
to now let's review what you've learned
I'll show you a character or a group of
characters and give you time to say them
ready as a word actually means
hand this is
z which one is the hiragana
it's this one the one that looks like
the angry Chia
leader
go this means
shoes cheu cheu is
mop
means
Apprentice T this means to
stand to to means
far it means to continue if you've ever
watch the Japanese TV dramas or anime I
think you have seen this
one
it means
which means University literally it
means big
school this means The Day After
Tomorrow means to calm
down great job you might ask if CH and
she sound very similar with the ductan
then how will I know which one to use
most of the time we use g g is very
rarely used in Japanese it is only used
for compound Ki which have ch as their
original sound for example blood in
Japanese is CH but nose bleed becomes
Han okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned in this
lesson you learn T
and and
G
and you've now mastered 20 characters
and 35 Japanese syllable sounds hi
everyone welcome to basic Japanese
writing the fastest easiest and most fun
way to master the Japanese
alphabet
[Music]
you've learned these 20 hiragana
characters in the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn five
new hilana
characters the first hilana character
for this lesson is
n
n think of Na as a complicated
nut are you confused between T and na
just remember that na looks more
complicated so it gets mixed up in a nut
also remember that the left side of T is
taller do you remember that is used as
the suffix for most adjectives these are
called e adjectives the other kind of
adjectives are the n adjectives this use
theana as the particle to connect two
nouns okay next up is the hiragana
character KN looks like a knee easy to
remember
right the third one is the
hiana to remember this character think
of a pair of Chopsticks holding a bunch
of
noodles
this is
the think of net as a snail hiding
behind a
nail net looks similar to n doesn't it
well just remember that you need a pair
of Chopsticks to be able to hold your
noodles so n has two lines sticking out
on top top of the curve and net just has
one and our final character for this
lesson is the hiragana
no
no it's easy to remember this one it's
like a no
sign no is also widely used hilana it is
the particle used to denote possession
let's see all the characters again now
now let's riew what you've learned I'll
show you a character or a word and give
you time to say them
ready KN just like a knee remember which
one is the H
top it's this one it does look like a
top doesn't it
G this also means letter remember this
one it's
set C it's a
c this means what what N means
what
this means
dog is
cat ni means
rainbow means
money it refers to your upper
back Nat is fermented
soybeans it's known to be very smelly
but it's very good for
you means please as a noun it also means
a
request great job are you wondering why
there's no D version of
n this is because the nend sound is
already voiced try to feel your throat m
there's a vibration right okay let's
wrap up this lesson by recapping what
you've learned in this lesson you learn
the hilana
characters and
no you've now mastered 25 characters and
40 Japanese syllable sounds hi everyone
welcome to basic Japanese writing the
fastest easiest and most fun way to
master the Japanese alphabet
[Music]
you've learned these 25 hiana characters
from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn five
new colors and 16 new sounds I promise
it will be easy so stay tuned to learn
all about
them the first hilana character for this
lesson is
h
h to remember ha imagine this part is a
capital letter H and then there's a
small a in front of it
h h might look similar to K so it may be
confusing to tell the difference between
them remember that ha has a hoop did you
miss the Duan last lesson well this
column can be modified by adding a Zan
as well can you can you guess what the
new sound will be after adding a duct to
ha it will be B ha ba
ha but wait there's one more Mark that
can modify the H column it's the H or
Mar mark it looks like a small circle
and it's placed in the same position as
the D then this Mark makes the consonant
of the syllable Prive and it's Unique to
this column H with a hand is
pronounced
ha ha
p a consonant explosive when there's a
big breast of air coming out of your
mouth when you say it P P try to feel
the difference
h h is also a popular hilana it's a
topic marking particle in Japanese so
the word or phrase that comes before it
is the topic of the
sentence but be careful ha is pronounced
differently when it's used as a topic
marking particle it will be pronounced
as
what for
example many speakers actually find it
hard to read this last example if it's
written just in hilana this is where
Kani is very useful knowing which part
is a word and which part is a particle
makes it easy to read
Japanese okay next up is the
hilana can you see a smiling mouth going
he he he he
he
now let's add a DCT to he he with a DCT
is pronounced as be he be he
be and how will it sound like with a h
it's going to
be
he the third hiana for this lesson
is it's not who or who but somewhere in
between who
who it's a sound unique to Japanese so
let's remember it with something unique
to Japan Mount
Fuji let's try adding a duct to Fu as
well how do you think it will sound it's
pronounced as B listen carefully
H
H now let's try it with a hak then it
becomes
p
p next is the hiragana
character it looks like it's pointing up
to heaven where the sky is
let's modify he with a
DCT it's now pronounced as be
he and when he is modified with a hand
it will be pronounced
as he is the particle used to indicate
the place towards which something is
moving
moving just like ha he also changes
pronunciation when used as a particle in
this case we pronounce it as just like
the listen to some
examples our final character for this
lesson is
the try by imagining a horse's face with
its man on the left side to remember
this
character does ho remind you of ha they
both have a hoop so how do you remember
them well H has two horizontal lines and
ha only has one so this means ha has
only half the lines and H has the whole
lot what does H sound like with the
with a DCT is pronounced
b
b b and with a hand it will be
po
po po let's see all calaes again H or if
it's used as a
particle
he p
h he or if it is used as a
particle now let's give you what you've
learned I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them
ready remember that is like Mount
Fuji
B it has the handon which makes it
plosive so it's
pet now remember it's a complicated nut
right which one is the
hiana it's this one with the hoop and H
the horizontal lines as
H
go Han this means
flower it's your
knee this could be Hashi meaning
Chopsticks or Hashi which means means
brid hush means
strange Hanabi this is Japanese for
fireworks literally it means firef
flowers this means
complicated is a
drawer
it means
perfectionist great job as you learn
more characters you notice that some of
them look similar try making a chart of
your own grouping similar characters and
list down a unique feature you can find
for each so that when you see it you can
identify that specific character easily
okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned in this
lesson you learn ha B and P he B and
P and
P
and
and and
po you've now mastered 30 Cales and 56
Japanese syllable sounds hi everyone
welcome to basic Japanese writing the
fastest easiest and most fun way to
master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned these 30 hilana
characters from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn five
new hiragana
characters the first hiragana character
for this lesson is
ma
ma try looking at it as a a man in a
mask and you remember
ma okay next up is
Thea
me think of it as the musical
note the third one is
theana
moo looks like a cow and what do Cows
say
Moo this is the hiana
character does Matt remind you of this
character the one where the Chopsticks
are holding some
noodles but look this part is now
missing this means that the Chopsticks
dropped some noodles and made a
mess and our final character for this
lesson is
the to remember more just imagine it as
a monitor lizard this part is its huge
long
tail Ma and mo might be confusing
because they look similar but just
remember that Ma is the one with the
mouth let's see all the characters again
ma now let's give you what you've
learned I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them
ready me me actually means
I
M which one is
aana it's this one holding more
noodles just like a
tunami
s remember not to mistake it for
CH Mai this means town or
city this could be a which means rain a
which means
candy atama it's an important part of
your body it means head
this is kimono it literally means
something you
wear Tam make
it it means
sign my my means everyday speaking of
which I hope you're practicing every day
trying saying this long
one was it difficult yes it is Musashi
means
difficult great job do you have other
nemonic suggestions to make remembering
hiana easier share them in the comments
below okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned in this
lesson you learned hiragana characters
Ma and
mo you
you've now mastered 35 characters and 61
Japanese syllable sounds hi everyone
welcome to basic Japanese writing the
fastest easiest and most fun way to
master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned these 35
hiragana characters from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn five
new hilana
characters the first hilana character
for this this lesson is
l
l think of L as a rabbit sitting on its
hind
legs is it hard to tell between LA and
Chi just remember that Chi has the top
part crossing
over okay next up is the hilana
color
Le looks like a river easy to remember
right e and Le look very similar
especially when L one way to remember
the difference is that the right stroke
of re is longer and it flows like a
river the third one is the
hiragana to remember this Cal
think of it as a hand holding a
ruby this is the
hilana think of le as a reindeer looking
up and our final Cal for this lesson
is
remember L it looks very similar right
but where's the ruby the hand was
holding it's gone now so you got
robed let's see all the characters
again now let's give you what you've
learned I'll show you a character or a
word and give you time to say them ready
which one is
theana it's this one with the flowing
last stroke just like a
river n remember not to confuse it
with so
remember the Cuckoo's
beak
sh Sal this means
monkey har it means sunny or clear
weather
Lau means convenient or
comfortable ofo means bath and it's an
important part of Japanese
culture this means
medicine on on is a famous Japanese dish
and you eat it with just your
hands
this means stuffed
toy great job are there still other
similar letters you are confused about
post them in the comments and we'll try
to help you out okay let's wrap up this
lesson by recapping what you've learned
in this lesson you
learned and please note that we skipped
the Y column this time so that we could
discuss all the Japanese graphs in the
next
lesson you've now mastered 40 characters
and 66 Japanese syllable sounds hi
everyone welcome to basic Japanese
writing the fastest easiest and most fun
way to master the Japanese
alphabet you've learned these 40 hilana
characters from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn three
new characters and 33 new C sounds yes
33 11 * 3 33 new sounds got to learn
them
all the first hilana character for this
lesson is
y
y yeah actually looks like a yuck the
two horns are protruding on
Top This is the hilana Cala you
you
you there's a magical way to remember
you just think of a
unicorn you is also a popular H but not
because of how it's used in a sentence
but because it is used as a mark for
onent or hot spring bath you actually
stands for o meaning hot
water our refiner can leure for this
lesson is theana
Yo
Yo to remember Y imagine a yoyo dangling
from a
finger there's another set of syllables
in Japanese which is formed by adding
the Y U or your sound to a consonant
plus an e
sound this time the the y u and your
characters are written
smaller these are the Japanese diagraphs
called y even though they look longer
they are still the same length in
syllables as the previous characters
that you've
learned
Sha
technically you could also make a
diagraph with G but it's not in use
anymore one thing to note is that you
need to be careful when writing or
pronouncing them they are written
smaller and they are pronounced by
gliding to the Y sound and not
pronouncing the e sound doing it
otherwise might get you a completely
different
word here's an example do means Dragon
but do means
reason another one is co meaning today
however when you pronounce the the e
sound and say k it means handy or
skilled let's see all the characters
again
yo and the
diagraphs
now let's give you what you've learned
I'll show you a character or a word and
give you time to say them
ready y
you the magical
unicorn
yeah
no ah remember the
Apple
she you it means means
dream Yama Yama is
Mountain y this means
cheapi means cooking are you good at
it K it means
company Judo
Judo is the national sports of
Japan this means homework you should do
it being it means Hospital you don't
want to confuse it with bin meaning
hairdresser great job do you like
listening to Japanese songs try finding
the lyrics in Japanese with fana online
and practice your h by reading them and
eventually singing
them okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've
learned in this lesson you learned the
hilana characters ya Yu and yo and all
Japanese
diagraphs you've now mastered 43
characters in 99 Japanese syllable
sounds wow hi everyone welcome to basic
Japanese writing the firstest easiest
and most fun way to master the Japanese
alphabet you have learned these 43
hilana characters from the previous
lessons in this lesson you learn three
new characters and just two new sounds
yes you've learned one of them before
stay tuned to find out which
one the first hilana character for this
lesson is
what what do you remember that the
hilana ha is pronounced as what if it's
a particle well the W sound is actually
signified by this character as
well to remember what think of it as a
white
swine many people have a hard time
remembering
NE and because left Hales look the same
hopefully our neonics can come to the
rescue remember net is the snail with a
spiral in its shell there is a reindeer
looking up in the sky and what is a
white swan floating on the
water this is the hilana
character what it is also commonly said
as o
o
try to think of w as a crack in the
wall what is a very distinct character
it is never used in a word but instead
it functions as the object marking
particle so whenever you say this it
means that the word before it is the
object of the
sentence for
example this means I ate an apple the
object of the
verb or at is lingo or apple and it's
the one that comes before W our final
character for this lesson is
the this one's easy it looks like an
italized
N is also special
because you can never start a word with
it it could only be found in the middle
or at the end of words one more thing
that's special about is that its
pronunciation varies a bit depending on
the syllable that comes after
it it can sometimes have an N sound when
it comes before a b or P sound for
example com and compai and sometimes it
can have a n sound when it comes before
a g sound like in hangaku
let's see all the characters
again or o and
finally now let's riew what you've
learned I'll show you a character or a
word and give your time to say them
ready what it looks like a crack in the
wall
right yo
which one is theana
what it's this
one remember it's not sh it's
sh Ka this means
River
n it means Circle it's also the Japanese
currency yen in Japanese we call it
n is I or
me this means
music shim it's a
newspaper since after comes we pronounce
it
as means
mother this means to drink
water this means to eat
vegetables great job did you know there
used to be hiragana characters for we
and we however just like how W is
pronounced interchangeably as o we and
we was also pronounced as the vows i and
e so they become obsolete you never know
but maybe what might become obsolete in
the future as
well okay let's wrap up this lesson by
recapping what you've learned in this
lesson you learned the hilag characters
w w
and you've now mastered all 46
characters and all 101 Japanese cable
Sounds here are the 46 sagana galaxies
they are used mainly for Japanese words
and as grammatical particles these are
the five vowel sounds and the rest are a
combination of a consonant and a vowel
sound except
for this is the D or 10 Mark that makes
the consonant of the syllable voice it
can modify the characters under the k s
t and H columns on the other hand this
is the handen or Maru Mark and it's
exclusively used for the h column it
makes the consonant sound posive
Japanese diagraphs are formed by adding
a small Y U or yo to a consonant plus an
e
they are pronounced by gliding to the Y
sound and not pronouncing the E
pronunciation of hilana characters is
always the same except for these
characters with originate
pronunciations ha is pronounced W when
it's used as the topic marking
particle he is pronounced E when it's
used as a
preposition W is actually more commonly
pronounced as o and can sometimes be
pronounced n or depending on the
syllable that comes after
it congratulations you now know all the
syllable sounds native to Japanese but
wait we are not done yet did you know
that around 10% of Japanese is made of
long words from English you will already
know many Japanese words just by
learning the long words in Katakana so
you definitely don't want to miss out on
them
[Music]