trying to learn kanji click here to get
a free ebook and study along with this
[Music]
lesson hi welcome to the Japanese kanji
video series my name is Alicia and I'm
joined by hi everyone I'm Risa in this
series we will teach you the best method
for learning Japanese kanji and teach
you some of the most useful Kani
characters along the way that's right
and we are here to help guide you on
your journey in this first episode
you'll learn exactly what kanji is and
why you need it the best method of
learning kanji and about the building
blocks that make up a kanji character
okay Risa let's get right into it first
let's explain what kanji is
exactly it's quite simple actually Kani
is the use of Chinese characters in
Japanese writing so Japanese actually
uses Chinese characters in part of its
writing that's that's because Japanese
writing actually originated from China
right right a long time ago Japan only
used Chinese Cales today we use three
different scripts together to write
Japanese those three scripts
areana kak and Kani so for comparison
English only uses one script the English
alphabet but Japanese uses three
different ones kanji is the
interpretation of Chinese characters
into Japanese and hiragana and Katakana
are scripts created after by Japanese
people you can kind of think of the
latter two as the Japanese alphabet we
refer to them as Ka learning Kana is
easy it's just like learning the
alphabet you learn a limited number of
letters and using those letters you can
put them together to form words on their
own though they don't really hold any
meaning kanji however is different there
are thousands of them and hidden beneath
each one lies a secret message one Kani
character can say more than 100 of these
letters because it represents an idea a
wealth of meaning can be uncovered from
this Single Character the concept and
meaning however will only reveal itself
if you know where to look and this is
the true power of Kani okay now that we
know what kanji is how do we actually
start learning
kanji there are many ways to start
learning Kani the most obvious way
although not the most effective
is to Simply memorize them like learning
the alphabet or learning new words you
can start learning kanji by memorizing a
few each day every day until you've
memorized them all unlike learning the
alphabet however which consists of only
a small set of letters there are
thousands and thousands of kanji
characters each with their own unique
concept and meaning you can memorize the
alphabet in a few days but memorizing
every country there is let's just say
that should be active for a very very
long time and and let's hope that you
don't forget a few along the way
memorizing each individual coni one by
one just isn't practical there are
simply too many of them thankfully
there's a more effective way to learn
Kani and that's by learning the
radicals a kanji character can be broken
down into smaller components these
smaller components are called radicals
you can think of radicals simply as the
building blocks of kanji every kanji
character has at least one radical
sometimes the radical itself can be a
Kani on its own and several radicals put
together could be another kji by
learning radical the building blocks of
kanji you can understand the general
meaning of kanji characters you've yet
to learn instead of learning individual
Kani characters one at a time we
essentially learn the building blocks
instead you only have to learn a few
radicals to be able to read some of the
most common kanji characters out there
in this series we'll teach you 10 ful
radicals that'll get you started
learning kanji quickly and easily we've
covered quite a lot of things already so
why don't we wrap up the first lesson
and recap on what we've learned in this
lesson you learn that kanji is the
interpretation of Chinese characters
into Japanese writing kanji are
characters that represent an idea and
therefore contain a wealth of meaning
and the quickest and most effective way
to learn kanji is by watching this
series at japanesepod101.com where we
teach the building blocks of kanji
radicals in the next lesson we'll teach
you one of the most common useful and
basic radicals used in kanji the person
radical see you in the next lesson bye
bye hi everyone welcome to the Japanese
kanji video series in this lesson you'll
learn your very first radical the person
[Music]
radical take a look at these conji
characters can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
conji characters in the previous lesson
we learned that conji characters are
made up of radicals the building blocks
of kanji these radicals give us
tremendous Clues to the meaning behind
kanji characters can you identify the
common element in all of these conji
characters it's this part here this
particular radical is called me it's
otherwise known as the person radical
and it's used in some of the most common
of all kanji characters let's take a
look at it in more
detail on its own the person radical
looks like this we mentioned before that
some radicals can be kanji on their own
this radical is one such example the
meaning behind this particular coni is
human or person when this radical
appears as a part of another conji like
in these examples the appearance changes
slightly when it's a component like this
it adds the meaning of human or person
to the entire kanji character if you can
identify a ladal in a Kani character
there's a good chance that you can guess
the meaning of the character itself the
first kanji has the person radical
paired with this second character this
second character is also a common
radical and conji in itself it's the
character for tree when paired together
a person leaning on a tree means that
they're resting so this kanji character
means to rest the second kanji has the
person radical paired with this
character it's identical to the tree
character from before except with this
small horizontal line at the bottom the
meaning of this character is root or
trunk when paired together the root or
trunk of a person refers to their body
so this kji means body the last kanji
has the person radical paired with the
character for word human and word paired
together means trust or faith can you
see how we can determine the meaning of
each coni character by identifying the
radicals in them by following this
process we can deduce the meaning of
Kani characters we've yet to learn and
the more ladal you learn the easier it
will be to learn even more
Kani the person radical most commonly
occurs in the left position as can be
seen in these examples this will be the
position you'll most likely encounter it
in sometimes though you may find it in
the top of a Ki character this position
is known as the crown position as can be
seen in some of these examples however
this is L common just remember the left
and Crown positions and you'll be able
to identify the person radical okay now
let's learn how to write this
radical learning the stroke order of
radicals is important because it's
designed to help you flow from one
character to the next knowing how to
write a radical demonstrates
understanding of the components that
make up a kanji character while it may
not seem important at first particularly
for basic Kani characters learning the
proper stroke order is important down
the line when you learn more difficult
kanji some kanji characters are written
in many strokes and they can get very
complex so unless you're writing it in
the correct order the end result may be
unreadable therefore it's important for
you to know how to write each K
character in the correct order while
there are some rules to coni stroke
order there are no hard and fast rules
to learning them the more radicals you
learn how to write the easier and more
intuitive it will become to write whole
kanji characters now let's take a look
at the stroke order of the person
radical the person radical is is very
simple there are only two strokes when
the Lao is on its own it looks like this
the first stroke starts from the upper
Center and then carves down to the
bottom left the second stroke starts a
tiny bit below the first stroke and goes
directly to the bottom right when this
radical is a part of another conji it
usually takes on the left position and
the appearance is distorted a little the
first stroke goes from right to left at
the top and the second stroke stroke
attaches to the center of the first
stroke and goes all the way down when
the radical takes the crown position
it's written in much the same way it
starts from the upper Center going right
to left and then from left to right and
that's it you're
done Kani characters can have multiple
readings they're usually broken down
into two groups called on and kunon
readings the on reading mimics the
original sound made in Chinese while the
reading is a revised reading used
to integrate with the Japanese alphabet
the only way to determine which reading
to use is mainly via the context on
readings will usually be used when
multiple Kani characters are grouped
together into a compound word whereas
kunon readings will usually be used when
it's a standalone conji like in the
first example in the case of the
original examples the on and kunon
readings of each are as
follows yes for the conji meaning to
rest
for the body conji and shin for the
trust conji reading kji may be difficult
to start off this but they'll only get
easier as you learn more lus over
time in this lesson you learned about
the person radical the idea behind this
radical is person or human you also
learn the kanji characters for person
rest body and Trust in which this
radical appears it's most commonly found
in the left position making Mak it
appear like this and it's written with
two strokes going from right to left and
then top to bottom hi everyone welcome
to the Japanese kanji video series in
this lesson you'll learn the human legs
radical take a look at these coni
characters can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
Kani characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these kanji
characters it's this part here it looks
like a pair of legs this particular
radical is
called
or it's the human legs radical and it's
used in some of the most common of all
kanji let's take a look at it in more
detail in some of the previous lessons
you learned that some radicals are conji
characters on their own this is the
first radical we've encountered that
isn't a kanji character in itself this
basically means that you'll only
encounter it as a component in other
conji character characters the meaning
behind this radical is legs particularly
those of a person unlike the previous
radicals that we've learned the meaning
of the human legs radical is less
literal It generally alludes more to the
sense of structural support that our
legs provide us with from left to right
the first kanji means origin or
Foundation the second means light or to
shine and the third character means to
see if you think of these Kani
characters from the Viewpoint of SP the
meaning of each character makes much
more sense the first kanji has the human
legs radical at the bottom which is
connected to a wide horizontal line with
a smaller parallel horizontal line on
top the wide horizontal line represents
the body and the smaller horizontal line
represents the head notice how the legs
are connected and are supporting the
body the legs that are supporting the
body and head represent the foundation
or basis which is the meaning of this
Kani character the second kji has the
legs on the bottom once again with what
appears to be a fire burning on top Fire
evokes Light so the meaning of this
kanji is light and the foundation or
origin of the emitting Rays refers to
the point source light emanating from a
source means that it's shining so this
kanji can also mean to shine the final
kanji has human legs on the bottom
supporting the character for I and N
that is mobile is one that can see so
this Ki character means to
see the human legs radical will always
be at the bottom position where it's
supporting something just remember where
your legs are on your body and you won't
forget it where are your legs on the
bottom okay now let's learn how to write
this
radical the human legs radical only has
two strokes the first stroke starts near
the center and curves from right to the
bottom left left the second stroke also
starts near the center but it goes
straight down and then flattens out at
the floor only to flck Upward slightly
the beginning of each stroke usually
connects to another radical so keep that
in mind and that's it you're
done the human legs radical isn't a
kanji on its own so you'll only see it
as a part of another conji in the case
of the original examples common readings
are
for the origin or foundation
conji for the conji meaning to shine and
K for the conji meaning to
see in this lesson you learned about the
human legs radical the idea behind the
human legs radical is support this
radical isn't a Kani character on its
own so you'll only see it in other coni
characters such as the foundation shine
and C kanji characters that you learned
in this lesson You'll Always Find this
radical in the bottom position and it's
written with two vertical Strokes one
curved stroke and one that flattens out
and flicks upward slightly hi everyone
welcome to the Japanese kanji video
series in this lesson you'll learn the
radical take a look at these conji
characters can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
Kani characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these Kani
characters it's this part here it looks
like a cross this particular radical is
called J which literally means 10 in
Japanese the 10 radical is used in some
of the most common kanji characters
let's take a look at it in more
detail the 10 radical means exactly that
10 but it also means completeness likely
because Chinese uses a BAS 10 number
system as you can see the 10 radical is
also a k character on its own from left
to right the first Ki means 10 the
second means thousand the third
character means noon and the fourth
character means old the second kanji has
the 10 radical at the bottom paired with
the person radical the very first
radical you learned we covered it in
lesson two in the olden days people
aspired to live to 100 so if one person
Liv to 100 then the idea is that 10
human lifetimes would equate to a
thousand which is the meaning of this
character thousand the third conji means
noon to remember this kanji identify
that the 10 radical is at the bottom and
imagine that the top two strokes signify
the number two 10 + 2 = 12 and 12 means
that it's noon the origin of the fourth
and final conji is a little contested
but it has the 10 radical on top below
it is mouth another useful radical which
we will learn in the the next lesson
it's thought that something that has
completed its cycle and relating to the
mouth means that it's old food or food
that has dried out when something is dry
it hardens and so this Ki carries a
sense of something that is old dry or
hard the 10 radical will usually sit in
the bottom position and connect with
another radical above it it can also be
in the crown position when it in this
position the bottom radical is likely to
be the mouse radical in which case it
add the sense of oldness dryness or
hardness that we talked about before be
careful when trying to identify this
radical though as there will often be
crosses in many kanji due to the nature
in which kanji characters are written
some characters may look like they use
the 10 radical but don't be fooled
here's a small list of characters which
do and do not use the 10
radical okay okay now let's learn how to
write this
radical the 10 radical is very simple it
only has two strokes the first stroke is
a horizontal one that goes from left to
right this horizontal stroke Rises ever
so slightly as it approaches the right
side the second stroke is a vertical
stroke that starts at the top and goes
down to the bottom splitting the first
horizontal stroke in half and forming a
cross sign when this radical is part of
another conji it'll usually connect to
another radical at the vertical ends of
the second stroke and that's it you're
done when the 10 radical is on its own
the kanji can be read as for the on
reading and to for the reading and when
the 10 radical is part of another conji
like in the original examples common
readings
are for the coni mean meaning
thousand for the conji meaning
noon for the conji meaning
old in this lesson you learned about the
10 radical the 10 radical looks like a
cross it signifies the number 10 and the
idea of completeness you also learn the
kanji characters for 10 thousand noon
and old in which this radical appears
it's commonly found in the bottom or
crown position and it's written with one
one horizontal stroke and one vertical
stroke hi everyone welcome to the
Japanese kanji video series in this
lesson you'll learn the mouth
[Music]
radical take a look at these conji
characters can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
kanji characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these coni
characters it's this part here this
particular radical is called
or the mouth radical is used in some of
the most common Kani characters let's
take a look at it in more
detail the mouse radical stands for
exactly that the mouse keep in mind
though that it encapsulates the many
senses of the word mouth and isn't
limited to the mouth of a person or
animal the mouth of a river for instance
alludes to an opening where water moves
through to enter an ocean the mouth
radical embodies this sense of the word
too from left to right the first K means
MTH the second means older brother the
third character means old and the fourth
character means same this radical is a
conji by itself as seen in the first
example the second conji has the mouth
radical on top and the human legs
radical which we learned in lesson four
on the bottom the third conji has the
mouth radical on the bottom and the 10
radical which we learned in the previous
lesson on top do you remember this kji
kexa it's the ca for or the fourth kanji
has the mouth radical enclosed in a type
of hood representing a group a group of
people who share one voice have the same
opinion so the meaning of this kji is
same or
equal the mouth radical appears in
multiple positions it can appear in the
crown position like in the Kani for
older brother or it can appear at the
the bottom in the foot position like in
the Ki for
old and just as often it can appear in
the right position like in this SC
character meaning Harmony as you can see
the mouth radical appears in many
different positions so keep your eyes
peeled okay now let's learn how to write
this
radical the mouth radical is very simple
it's written in three strokes and it
looks like a box the first stroke occurs
on the left side and is a vertical
stroke that goes from top to bottom the
second looks like a right corner and
starts from left to right and then bends
downwards it's important to note that
this second stroke should be completed
in one smooth motion finally close the
Box by connecting the first stroke to
the second stroke at the bottom and
that's it you're
done when the mouth radical is on its
own the Kani can be read as coold for
the own reading and for the reading and
when the mouth radical is a part of
another
conji for the older brother
kanji for the Kani meaning old
and for the conji meaning same or
equal in this lesson you learned about
the mouth radical the mouth radical
looks like a square
the idea behind this radical
encapsulates all senses of the word
mouth equivalent to English you also
learn the kanji characters for mouth
older brother old and same or equal in
which this radical appears it can be
found in multiple positions the crown
foot or right position and it's written
with one vertical stroke one right
corner stroke and one connecting
horizontal stroke hi everyone welcome to
the Japanese kanji video series in this
lesson you'll learn the one radical
take a look at these kanji characters
can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
conji characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these kanji
characters it's this part here it's a
single horizontal stroke this particular
radical is called it which literally
means one the one radical is used in
some of the most common coni characters
let's let's take a look at it in more
detail the one radical means exactly
that the number one from left to right
the first Ki means one the second means
word or era the third character means
above and the fourth character means
Char as you can see in the first example
the one radical is also a conji
character on its own the second coni is
actually a reduction of another conji
meaning leaf the leaves and branches
that grow on top of the tree are thought
to represent a different age or a
generation of leaves and branches the
war REO here unifies the leaves and
branches from a generation the meaning
of this kanji can be interpreted as word
or UK the third kanji is an idiogram
which shows the concept of up or above
by having one horizontal line above
another the fourth conji is a pictogram
the top portion represents the baby's
head while the lower portion represents
its body wrapped in a blanket the one
radical here signifies the baby's arm
spreading while growing into a child so
the meaning of this kanji is
child the one radical appears in many
different positions it commonly sits in
the crown position like in thei for word
or era another common position is at the
bottom in the foot position as seen in
the k for
above okay now let's learn how to write
this
radical the one radical is incredibly
simple to write it has only one stroke
the concept of one is represented by a
single stroke that goes from left to
right it's important to note that this
horizontal stroke Rises ever so slightly
as it approaches the right side and
that's it you're done
when the one radical is on its own the
Kani can be read
as for the own reading and for the
reading when the one radical is part of
another
conji for the world or Epoch
coni for the conji meaning above
and for the child conji
in this lesson you learned about the one
radical the one radical looks like a
single horizontal stroke and it
signifies the concept of one you also
learn the Kani characters for one world
or Epoch above and child in which this
radical appears it's most commonly found
in the crown or bottom position and it's
written with just one horizontal stroke
going from left to right hi everyone
welcome to the Japanese kanji video
series in this lesson you'll learn the
word radical
[Music]
take a look at these kanji characters
can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
Kani characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these kanji
characters it's this part here this
particular radical is called G the word
radical is used in some of the most
common kanji characters let's take a
look at it in more detail
the meaning for the word radical relates
to words or speech from left to right
the first Ki means to say the second
means to talk or Story the third
character means language and the fourth
character means plan as you can see in
the first example the word radical is a
coni character on its own did you spot
the smaller mous laico that we learned
in lesson six it's this part here the
other part above it it's actually the
heart radical the heart sparing from the
mouth is symbolic of
wordss or meaning to say you can imagine
the lines as words exiting the mouse the
second kanji has the word radical on the
left and this other character on the
right once again there's the small mouth
radical that we learned sitting at the
bottom there can you guess what the
radical on the right
is I'll give you a clue it's a physical
muscle in your
body the large radical on the right
represents the tongue here's the mouth
on the bottom and there's the tongue
sticking out of it do you see it now the
word radical paired with the tongue
radical gives you the Ki meaning to talk
the third kanji has the word radical on
the left and this other radical on the
right and guess what there's that mouth
radical again there's this other tiny
character above the mouth it means five
but y five it's traditionally thought
that we experience language through five
paths using our two eyes two ears and
our mouth which adds up to five together
this character stands for language the
fource kji is the word radical paired
with the 10 radical which we learned in
lesson five think for a moment and guess
what it might
mean remember the radical on the right
can mean 10 but it can also mean
complete the meaning of this kind is to
PL words thought to completion means
that something has been planned out
we've only learned six radicals so far
in this series but are you starting to
see how we can already break down and
guess the meanings of many coni
characters imagine what you could do if
you just learned a few more radicals
okay let's move
on the word radical will almost always
be in the left position as seen in the
original examples for talk language and
plan notice how the word radical is
squished horizontally when it's in the
left
position okay now let's learn how to
write this
radical the word radical is written in
seven strokes the first stroke is a
diagonal stroke that starts at the top
and goes from left to right the second
stroke is a long and flat horizontal
stroke which also goes from left to
right and sits just under the first
stroke
the third and fourth Strokes are
identical to the previous stroke except
shorter the last section is a box which
sits at the bottom it's written in the
same way as the mouse laico that we
learned in lesson six so the fifth
stroke is a vertical stroke that goes
from top to bottom on the left side the
sixth stroke goes from left to right
bends and continues
downwards the seventh and final stroke
closes the box at the bottom and that's
it you're
done when the word radical is on its own
the kanji can be read
as for the reading and E for the reading
when the word radical is part of another
conji for the talk
conji for the language conji and
K for the plan conji
in this lesson you learned about the
word radical it signifies word or speech
you also learned the kanji characters
for word talk language and plan in which
this radical appears it's almost always
in the left position and it's written
with seven strokes one diagonal three
horizontal and another three making a
box hi everyone welcome to the Japanese
kanji video series in this lesson you'll
learn the day
[Music]
radical take a look at at these conji
characters can you guess what they
mean by the end of this lesson you'll be
able to grasp the meaning behind these
conji characters first off can you spot
the radical that's common in all of
these kanji
characters it's this part here this
particular radical is called he or he
the day radical is used in some of the
most common kanji characters let's take
a look at it in more
detail the day radical is a Kani
character on its own it's a pictogram of
the sun and it means sun or day from
left to right the first kji means sun or
day the second means bright the third
character means time and the fourth
character means projection or reflection
the first kanji is actually one of two
kanji characters used to write Japan as
we mentioned before the first Ki means s
and the second character means root
since Japan is to the east of China and
the sun rises from the East Japan is
written as the land where the sun
originate or more commonly the Land of
the Rising Sun the second kanji has the
day radical on the left and this other
character on the right which means Moon
the Sun and Moon together are depicting
Daybreak where the sky changes rapidly
from night into day and so the meaning
of this character is bright the next
kanji has the day radical on the left
and this other character on the right
which which means temple in historic
times the time of day was announced by
chiming a large Bell at the temple so
day and Temple together means time the
fourth conji has the day radical on the
left again and this other character
meaning the center or middle of a
person's body the character on the right
is actually a pictograph of a man a man
standing next to the Sun alludes to the
idea of something being reflected or
projected which is the meaning of this
kanji okay let's move on
the day radical will usually appear in
the left position as seen in the
original examples will bright time and
reflect or project when the day radical
is part of another kanji character it
shrinks in size okay now let's learn how
to write this
radical the day retical is written in
four strokes the first stroke is a
vertical stroke starts on the left and
goes from top to bottom the second
stroke is a toe right hand corner it
connects with the first stroke and goes
left to right bends and then goes
straight down the third stroke is a
horizontal stroke that occurs at the
halfway point and goes left to right the
fourth and final stroke is a horizontal
stroke closing out the box and that's it
you're
done when the day radical is AI on its
own it it can be read
as for the reading and he for the
reading and when the day radical is part
of another conji
May for the bright
conji for the time coni and
a for the reflect or project
conji in this lesson you learned about
the day radical the day radical looks
like this and it represents the Sun or
day you also learn the coni characters
for sun or day bright time and reflect
or project in which this radical appears
it usually appears in the left position
and it's written with four strokes one
vertical a right- hand corner stroke and
two horizontal Strokes hi everyone
welcome to the Japanese kanji video
series in this lesson you'll learn the
movement
[Music]
radical take a look at these kanji
characters can you guess what they mean
by the end of this lesson you'll be able
to grasp the meaning behind these kanji
characters first off can you spot the
radical that's common in all of these
coni
characters it's this part here this
particular radical is called sh the
movement radical is used in some of the
most common kanji characters let's take
a look at it in more
detail the meaning behind this radical
is movement or path this radical doesn't
exist on its own so you'll only find it
in other kji characters from left to
right the first kji means near the
second means to R the third character
means weak and the fourth character
means to carry the first kanji has the
movement radical in the bottom
surrounding position and the portion
above it is the character for axe the
function of an axe is essentially to
chop things and to make them smaller so
together a small movement can mean that
something is nearby so the meaning of
this character is close or
nearby the second kanji has the movement
radical in the bottom surrounding
position again and the portion above it
is the character for reverse or oppose
reverse movement means to return so this
kji means to return the third conji has
the radical in the same position but
this time with the character for
circumference movement around a
circumference alludes to a cycle this
particular kji is used to signify the
cycle of the week the final II has the
movement radical paired with the
character for Army a moving Army
transports weapons foods and goods
therefore the meaning of this kanji is
to transport or to carry okay let's move
on the movement radical will always be
in the bottom surrounding position and
because of this it's easily recognizable
s can be seen in the original examples
for near to return weak and to carry
okay now let's learn how to write this
radicle the movement reticle is written
in three Strokes the first stroke is a
short diagonal stroke that starts on the
left it goes from left to the bottom
right the second stroke looks like a
zigzag it starts below the first stroke
and goes left to right B going downwards
slightly and then repeat ensure that you
write the second stroke in one smooth
mod motion the third and final stroke is
a slightly curved horizontal stroke
which connects to the previous stroke it
starts from the left and goes all the
way to the right and that's it you're
done the movement radical isn't a kanji
character on its own so it'll only
appear as part of another conji when it
does it can be read as
follows for the coni meaning close or
nearby
H for the conji meaning return
for the conji meaning weak
and for the conji meaning to transport
or
carry in this lesson you learned about
the movement radical the concept behind
the character is movement or path you
also learn the kanji characters for
close return weak and transport or carry
in which this radical appears it'll
always appear in the bottom surrounding
position and it's written with three
Strokes a diagonal stroke a zigzag
looking stroke and a long curved
horizontal stroke hi everyone welcome to
the Japanese kanji video series in this
lesson you'll learn the gate
[Music]
radical take a look at these kanji
characters can you guess what they mean
by the end of this lesson you'll be able
to grasp the meaning behind these kanji
characters first off can you spot the
radical that's common in all of these
kanji
characters it's this part here it looks
like a gate or window with two sliding
doors this particular radical is
called the gate radical is used in some
of the most common Kani characters let's
take a look at it in more
detail the concept behind this radical
is gate division or Department from left
to right the first Ki means gate the
second means period the third character
means question and the fourth character
means to listen the first EX example
shows that this radical exists as a
kanji Cala on its own the second kanji
has the gate radical in the enclosing
position and this other character in the
center it's the day radical that we
learned in lesson 9 the concept of the
gate radical together with day gives us
a division of Z which we can associate
with a period of time the third kanji
has the same radical paired with another
character that we've learned it's the
mouth radical that we learned in lesson
six the department of of mouth means to
question or to ask the final kanji has
the same radical paired with another
character which is the kanji character
for ear the department of ear means to
lesson okay let's move
on the gate radical will always appear
in the enclosing position whether it's
by itself or if it's used in other coni
characters and because of this it's
easily recognizable as seen in the
original examples for gate period
question and to listen it will always be
in this
position okay now let's learn how to
write this
radical the gate radical is written in
eight Strokes the first stroke is a
straight vertical downstroke on the left
side the second stroke looks like a
right corner it connects to the fast
stroke and goes from left to right bends
and continues downward slightly the
third and fourth Strokes are two
horizontal Strokes that close out the
box the fifth stroke is a short vertical
stroke which starts near the center and
goes downward slightly the sixth stroke
connects to the previous stroke it goes
from left to right bends and continues
all the way downwards reaching the floor
where it flicks upward slightly towards
the center the last two strokes are
horizontal Strokes that close out the
books and that's it you're done
when the gate radical appears on its own
the coni character can be read as Mo for
the own reading and for the reading when
the gate radical is part of another
conji for the coni meaning
period for the conji meaning ask or
question
and for the conji meaning listen
in this lesson you learned about the
gate radical the concept behind the
character is gate division or Department
you also learn the Kani characters for
gate period ask or question and listen
in which this radical appears this
radical will always be in the enclosing
position and it's written in eight
Strokes demonstrated here well done you
just learned your 10th radical in this
series with this set of 10 radicals
alone you can deduce the meaning of 30%
of all practical everyday kanji in
Japanese was this video series helpful
let us know if you'd like to see more of
this series by replying in the comment
and if you want to learn more Japanese
or see more of Risa and I go to
japanesepod101.com we have a host of
different videos on various topics for
you to choose from we'll link them at
the end of the video good luck as you
continue learning Japanese stay tuned
for more kanji lessons in the future
until next time bye bye
n
[Music]